Guide to the J. D. McClatchy Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- October 2007 Acquisition, 1987-2006; 36; (40 boxes)
  - Mentions of J. D. McClatchy, 2001
    - Mentions of J. D. McClatchy, 2005-2006; 30 (Box 50)
    - Mentions of J. D. McClatchy, 2006; 24 (Box 51)
  - Opera
    - "1984", 2000-2007; 15 (Box 51)
    - "1984", 2000-2007; 30 (Box 52)
    - "Question of Taste", 1987-1997 (Box 53)
    - "Emmeline", 1996 July 27; 1; 02:03:34 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091244203)
    - "Emmeline" (compact discs) (Box 103)
    - "Emmeline", 1992-1998; 13 (Box 53)
      Audiovisual material in Box 110: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "Emmeline", 1993-1998; 17 (Box 54)
    - "Grendel", 2004-2006; 29 (Box 55)
    - "Orpheus Descending", 1993-1997; 30 (Box 56)
      There is an audiocassette related to this material that can be found in Box 110.
    - Lady arias from "Orpheus Descending", undated; 1; 00:23:34 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091244286)
      This audiocassette is related to material titled ""Orpheus Descending", 1993-1997 found in Box 56, reference number 412.
    - "Our Town", 2003-2007; 36 (Box 57)
      Includes 4 video discs and 2 compact discs
      Audiovisual material in Box 57: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "The Magic Flute", 2004-2007; 31 (Box 58)
      Includes 3 compact discs
      Compact discs in Box 58: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "The Magic Flute", 2005-2007; 18 (Box 59)
      Includes 1 VHS videocassette
      Videocassette in Box 59: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "Mystery tape", undated; YCALMSS705_0004; 1; 03:27:04; The tape consists of poor, grainy video of an opera. The words "archive tape" appears throughout the video. (Box 59, Item barcode 39002102370278)
    - "Miss Lonelyhearts", 2002-2007; 16 (Box 59)
    - "Miss Lonelyhearts", 2002-2006; 14 (Box 60)
      Includes 5 compact discs
      Compact discs in Box 60: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "Mario and the Magician", 1989-2004; 5 (Box 60)
    - "Mario and the Magician", Brooklyn College Opera Theater (audiocassette), undated; 1; 01:07:16 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091243775)
      Box 110 contains audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Use of original is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      This audiocassette is related to folders of material titled Mario and the Magician found in Box 60, reference number 437.
  - Poetry, Book Projects, and Other Writings
    - Hazmat, 2002; 15 (Box 61)
    - Division of Spoils, 2000 (Box 62)
    - Vintage Book of Contemporary World Poetry, undated (Box 62)
    - New York Community Trust, 1995-2000 (Box 62)
    - Twenty Questions, 1997-1998; 2 (Box 62)
    - Ten Commandments, 1997-1999; 3 (Box 62)
    - Reviews, 1997-1998; 4 (Box 62)
    - Horace, the Odes, 2001-2002; 10 (Box 62)
    - Horace, the Odes, 2000-2002; 9 (Box 63)
    - Notebook, Yale University Honorary Degrees, 2006; 3 (Box 63)
    - Notebook, Thornton Wilder: Collected Plays and Writings on Theater, undated (Box 63)
    - Thornton Wilder: Collected Plays and Writings on Theater, 2005 (Box 63)
    - Thornton Wilder: Collected Plays and Writings on Theater, 2005-2006; 7 (Box 64)
    - The Library of America: Thorton Wilder writings, undated; 3 (Box 64)
    - Thornton Wilder Society documents, 2000-2001; 4 (Box 64)
    - McClatchy lecture on American Writers at Home, given at the Garden Conservancy, broadcast on A&E book program, undated; YCALMSS705_0001; 1; 06:06:12 (Box 65, Item barcode 39002102370138)
      Videocassettes in Box 65: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      Note from the desk of J.D. McClatchy: My lecture on "American Writers at Home", given at the Garden Conservancy, broadcast on A + E book program.
    - 2000 Governor's Gold Medal for the Arts ceremony, Goodspeed Opera House, Haddam, CT, YCALMSS705_0002; 1; 03:39:18 (Box 65, Item barcode 39002102370146)
      Note from J.D. McClatchy included reads: I was given the 2000 governor's Gold Medal for the Arts. This tape is the ceremony (at the Goodspeed Opera House, Haddam) including my speech.
    - The Academy of American Poets presents: "The Poet's View: W. S. Merwin, John Ashbery, and Anthony Hecht", 2003; YCALMSS705_0003; 1; 00:58:50 (Box 65, Item barcode 39002102370153)
      McClatchy was the consultant for the series and appeared as an interviewer on the Asbery film
    - Genealogical material relating to the Simpson family, undated (Box 65)
    - Book Projects - Files, Reviews, Manuscripts, 1990-2002; 12 (Box 65)
    - Bright Pages - Correspondence, Editorial Matter, etc.
      - Knowles, John, 1999-2000 (Box 66)
      - Shapiro, Harvey, 2000-2001 (Box 66)
      - Massie, Robert K., 2000 (Box 66)
      - Sandy, Stephen, 1999 (Box 73)
      - Slavitt, David, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Kramer, Larry, 2000 (Box 73)
      - Wolfe, Tom, 1999-2000 (Box 66)
      - Trillin, Calvin, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Strand, Mark, undated (Box 66)
      - Guare, John, 1999-2000 (Box 66)
      - Matthews, William, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Lahr, John, 2000 (Box 66)
      - McGuane, Thomas, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Trudeau, Garry, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Hirson, David, 1999-2000 (Box 66)
      - Alexander, Elizabeth, undated (Box 73)
      - Buckley, Wililam F., 1999-2000 (Box 66)
      - Epstein, Leslie, 1995-2000 (Box 66)
      - Gurney, A. R., 1999 (Box 66)
      - Mathiessen, Peter, 1999-2000 (Box 66)
      - Monette, Paul, undated (Box 66)
      - Tilghman, Christopher, undated (Box 66)
      - Fagles, Robert, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Magowan, Robin, undated (Box 66)
      - Warren, Robert Penn, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Random House contracts, undated (Box 66)
      - Dramatist Play Service and Simon & Schuster contracts, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Hersey, John, undated (Box 66)
      - Hollander, John, undated (Box 66)
      - Stone, Robert, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Gill, Brendan, undated (Box 66)
      - Lord, Walter, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Tally, Ted, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Bradley, George, undated (Box 73)
      - Buckley, Christopher, undated (Box 66)
      - Warren, Rosanna, 2000 (Box 73)
      - Wasserstein, Wendy, undated (Box 66)
      - Hollander, Martha, undated (Box 73)
      - Leavitt, David, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Naylor, Gloria, 1999 (Box 66)
      - Romulus, Linney, 2000 (Box 73)
      - Kirchwey, Karl, 2000 (Box 73)
      - Lee, Chang-Rae, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Logan, William, 1999 (Box 73)
      - Messud, Claire, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Arnold, Craig, 2000 (Box 73)
      - Wetzsteon, Rachel, 2000 (Box 73)
      - Edwards, Jonathan, undated (Box 66)
      - Barlow, Joel, undated (Box 66)
      - Trumbull, John, undated (Box 66)
      - Dwight, Timothy, undated (Box 66)
      - Webster, Noah, undated (Box 66)
      - Pierpont, John, undated (Box 66)
      - Cooper, James Fenimore, undated (Box 66)
      - Willis, Nathaniel Parker, undated (Box 66)
      - Finch, Francis Miles, undated (Box 66)
      - Day, Clarence, undated (Box 66)
      - Johnson, Owen, undated (Box 66)
      - Lewis, Sinclair, 2000 (Box 66)
      - MacLeish, Archibald, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Barry, Philip, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Porter, Cole, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Wilder, Thorton, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, editorial matter, and notes, 2000; 3 (Box 66)
    - Manuscripts, Drafts of Poems, 2003-2007; 5 (Box 67)
    - American Writers at Home, Proofs
  - Other Papers
    - Business and Financial Records, 1983-2005; 8 (Box 67)
    - Reviews of Horace, the Odes, 2004 (Box 67)
    - DVD, 2007 (Box 67)
      DVD in Box 67: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Miscellaneous James Merrill Material, 2004 (Box 67)
    - Miscellaneous Teaching Material, 2003 (Box 67)
    - Grendel, music, undated; 2 (Box 67)
    - Miss Lonelyhearts, undated (Box 67)
    - Orpheus Descending, undated (Box 67)
    - Interviews with Authors for "Paris Review", 2003; 3 (Box 68)
    - Diaries, Journals, Notebooks, 1991-2004; 7 (Box 68)
    - "Poets of the Civil War", undated; 3 (Box 68)
    - Manuscripts, undated; 2 (Box 68)
    - "The Bridge of San Luis Rey", 2003 (Box 68)
    - Small press publications, 1987, 1994 (Box 68)
    - Enda St. Vincent Millay: poems, undated; 2 (Box 68)
    - Passport and driver's license, 2001 (Box 68)
    - Mold of teeth, undated (Box 71)
  - Oversize Material
    - Our Town, Proofs, 2004 (Box 69 (Oversize))
    - Emmeline, Proofs, 1998 (Box 69 (Oversize))
    - Hazmat, Proofs, 2002 (Box 69 (Oversize))
    - Mario and the Magician, Proofs, undated (Box 69 (Oversize))
    - American Writers at Home, Proofs, 2004 (Box 69 (Oversize))
    - Mentions of J. D. McClatchy, 2001 (Box 70 (Oversize))
    - Mentions of J. D. McClatchy, 2003 (Box 70 (Oversize))
    - "Carmen," proofs, 2000 (Box 70 (Oversize))
    - Miss Lonelyhearts, undated (Box 70 (Oversize))
    - Portrait sketches, undated (Box 70 (Oversize))
  - Computer media
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Reviews (can all go), 2007-ycal-11179-0001; 1 (Box 72)
      Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Letters of Recommendation Mario, 2007-ycal-11179-0002; 1 (Box 72)
    - Fastback, 2007-ycal-11179-0003; 1 (Box 72)
    - DOS 3.30.05, 2007-ycal-11179-0004; 1 (Box 72)
    - 1, 2007-ycal-11179-0005 (Box 72)
    - 2, 2007-ycal-11179-0006; 1 (Box 72)
    - 3, 2007-ycal-11179-0007; 1 (Box 72)
    - 4, 2007-ycal-11179-0008; 1 (Box 72)
    - 5, 2007-ycal-11179-0009; 1 (Box 72)
    - 6 Word Perfect 5.0, 2007-ycal-11179-0010; 1 (Box 72)
    - 7, 2007-ycal-11179-0011; 1 (Box 72)
    - 8, 2007-ycal-11179-0012; 1 (Box 72)
    - 9, 2007-ycal-11179-0013; 1 (Box 72)
    - 10, 2007-ycal-11179-0014; 1 (Box 72)
    - 11, 2007-ycal-11179-0015; 1 (Box 72)
    - McClatchy changes + Index PUP, 2007-ycal-11179-0016; 1 (Box 72)
    - Our Town First Draft 29.11.04, 2007-ycal-11179-0017; 1 (Box 72)
    - [no label information], 2007-ycal-11179-0018; 1 (Box 72)
    - HORACE INTRODUCTION AUTHOR ADDRESSES t of contents - title page, 2007-ycal-11179-0019; 1 (Box 72)
    - [no label information], 2007-ycal-11179-0020; 1 (Box 72)
    - [no label information], 2007-ycal-11179-0021; 1 (Box 72)
    - MISS LONELYHEARTS 2/11/86, 2007-ycal-11179-0022; 1 (Box 72)
    - [no label information], 2007-ycal-11179-0023; 1 (Box 72)
    - [no label information], 2007-ycal-11179-0024; 1 (Box 72)
    - [no label information], 2007-ycal-11179-0025; 1 (Box 72)
    - [no label information], 2007-ycal-11179-0026; 1 (Box 72)
    - [no label information], 2007-ycal-11179-0027; 1 (Box 72)
    - [no label information], 2007-ycal-11179-0028; 1 (Box 72)
    - [no label information], 2007-ycal-11179-0029; 1 (Box 72)
    - [no label information], 2007-ycal-11179-0030; 1 (Box 72)
    - [no label information], 2007-ycal-11179-0031; 1 (Box 72)
    - [no label information], 2007-ycal-11179-0032; 1 (Box 72)
- June 2012 Acquisition, circa 2004-2012; 2.21; (3 boxes)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 1278
  Box 76 (Computer discs): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 103 and 106 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  This portion of the collection consists of correspondence, printed material, writings, page proofs, audiovisual materials, computer discs, and other papers relating to Anthony Hecht, McClatchy's role as his literary executor, and Anthony Hecht: Selected Poems, edited by J. D. McClatchy.
  - Correspondence, writings, and other papers relating to Anthony Hecht and his literary estate., circa 2004-2012; 12 (Box 74)
  - Correspondence, writings, audiovisual material, and other papers relating to Anthony Hecht and his literary estate, circa 2004-2012; 6 (Box 75)
    Boxes 103 and 106 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - This Week: In Memorium, 2004-10-24; YCALMSS705_0005; 1; 00:04:38 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002093672286)
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. This videocassette has been digitized. Consult access services for further information.
    - Memorial service for Anthony Hecht, Guggenheim Museum, 2005-01-10; YCALMSS705_0006; 1; 01:25:42 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002093672294)
    - "BBC News - Brief Lives: Anthony Hecht", The Academy of American Poets, undated; 1; 00:25:05 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091243783)
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. This audiocassette is being reformatted. Consult access services for further information.
- November 2012 Acquisition, 1900-2012; 20.63; (26 boxes) + 2 broadside folders
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 1279
  Box 103 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 104 (Electronic media): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult access services for further information.
  Organized under seven headings: Correspondence; Writings; Subject files; Family papers; Photographs; Printed materials; Audiovisual materials.
  This portion of the collection consists of correspondence, writings, subject files, family papers, photographs, printed materials, and audiovisual materials. The bulk of these papers span the years 2006-2012, with some earlier writings, family papers, and photographs. Correspondence includes Yale Review business and papers related to McClatchy's term as president of the American Academy of Arts and Letters. Writings include poetry, edited collections, and opera writings.
  - Correspondence, 2007-2012
    - Invitations, thank you notes, letters to the editor of the Yale Review, royalty notifications, holiday greetings, business correspondence, and general correspondence, 2007; 13 (Box 77)
    - Invitations, thank you notes, letters to the editor of the Yale Review, royalty notifications, holiday greetings, business correspondence, and general correspondence, 2007; 4 (Box 78)
    - Invitations, thank you notes, postcards, general correspondence, Academy of Arts and Letters and Library of America business, enclosed poems and articles, royalties notifications, and other personal documents, 2008; 19 (Box 79)
      Includes a letter from John Updike.
    - Invitations, thank you notes, letters to the editor of the Yale Review, royalty notifications, holiday greetings, business correspondence, and general correspondence, 2009-2010; 11 (Box 80)
    - Invitations, thank you notes, letters to the editor of the Yale Review, royalty notifications, holiday greetings, business correspondence, and general correspondence, 2009-2010; 12 (Box 81)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters correspondence and other papers, 2009-2012; 10 (Box 82)
      Board correspondence includes nominations, ballots, and other business. Other material includes committee lists, notes and correspondence, general correspondence, speech notes and remarks, news clippings, and other printed material.
  - Writings, 1990s-2012
    - Manuscripts, related correspondence, 1990s-2000s; 13 (Box 83)
    - Manuscripts, related correspondence, 1990s-2000s; 11 (Box 84)
    - Mercury Dressing 3rd pass proof, 2008 (Box 85 (Oversize))
    - Manuscripts, related correspondence, 2007-2008; 7 (Box 86)
    - Manuscripts, related correspondence and printed material, 2011; 12 (Box 87)
    - Opera writings and related printed material, 2006-2011; 11 (Box 88)
      Titles include: Grendel, The Magic Flute, Vincent, The Enchanted April, The Secret Agent and 1984.
    - Opera writings and related printed material, 2010-2012; 3 (Box 89)
      Titles include: Our Town
    - Opera writings, 2010-2011; 25 (Box 90)
      Drafts of Seven Mozart Librettos.
    - Opera writings, 2010-2011; 25 (Box 91)
  - Subject files, 2006-2011
    - Mentions of J. D. McClatchy, 2007; 10 (Box 92)
      Includes clippings, printed material, manuscripts, and correspondence.
    - Mentions of J. D. McClatchy, 2008; 9 (Box 93)
      Includes clippings, printed material, correspondence, manuscripts, print outs, proofs for James Merrill: Selected Poems, and printed material.
    - Mentions of J. D. McClatchy, 2008-2010; 5 (Box 94 (Oversize))
      Includes clippings and printed material.
    - Mentions of J. D. McClatchy, 2009-2010; 10 (Box 95)
    - Mentions of J. D. McClatchy, 2011; 6 (Box 96)
    - 2 graduate hoods given for advanced or honorary degrees, 2006, 2011 (Box 97)
  - Family papers, 1900-2009
    - Family bibles, 1900-1916; 2 (Box 98)
    - Mary Jane McClatchy's day books spanning more than 6 decades, 1947-2009; 28 (Box 99)
  - Photographs, 1900s, 1945, undated
    - Framed family photographs, 1900s, 1945; 3 (Box 100 (Oversize))
    - Photograph of J.D. McClatchy's father, 1985 (Box 101 (Broadside))
  - Printed Materials, 2008-2011
    - Posters and broadsides, 2008-2011 (Box 94 (Oversize))
      Includes poster for The Secret Agent, broadside, "Poetery, and broadside, "Whatever Happened to Rosie Rowe?"
    - 2 copies of broadside poem, "Zion," by Robert Perkins (Box 102 (Broadside))
  - Audiovisual Materials, 2007
    - McClatchy on Opera, 2007 February 28; 1; 00:58:19; A high amount of hiss can be heard on the tape. (Box 103, Item barcode 39002091244260)
      Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      A note found with this audiocassette reads: Dear Sandy, As promised, and with great apprectiation. Love, Helen